Guide to the Hartt guest artists collection ARCH078
University of Hartford Archives & Special Collections
Hartt guest artists collection
1950-2010
1962-1979
University of Hartford Archives & Special Collections
ARCH078
1.69 Linear Feet (5 containers)
Materials pertaining to guest artists at the Hartt School primarily in the 1960s and 70s.
Conditions Governing Access
The collection is open to all researchers.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains correspondence, biographical information, programs, newspaper clippings, and photographs of guest artists who visited or performed at the Hartt School primarily in the 1960s and 1970s.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged in two series: I. Publicity and Planning Documents and II. Photographs.
Existence and Location of Copies
Portions of the collection have been digitized and can be accessed at: http://mdid3.hartford.edu. Public access to the digital repository is limited to the University of Hartford Campus. Computers are available to the public at the Harrison Libraries. Off-campus access is available for University of Hartford students, faculty, and staff with their university email and password.
Musicians; Photographs; Hartt School
- Publicity and Planning Documents
  - Actors' Institute, 1979 - 1980 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Alban Berg String Quartet, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Albright, William, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 3, Box Shared Small Oversized 1)
  - American String Quartet, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Anderson, Marian, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Babbitt, Milton, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Barnett, David, 1969 - 1970 (Box 1, Folder 7 - 8)
  - Benny, Jack, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Berg, Christopher, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Bloom, Arthur, 1975 - 1980 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Boszormenyi-Nagy, Bela, undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Brieff, Frank, 1963, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Brubeck, Dave, 1978, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Burakoff, Gerald, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Butler, Henry, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Cavender, George, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Chase, Bill, 1972 - 1973 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Crozier, Catharine, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Currier, Donald, 1972, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Davenny, Ward, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - De La Torre, Rey, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Donald, Mattran, undated (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Duke, Jordan, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Duckworth, Guy, 1969 - 1970 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Eisman, Lawrence, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Fennell, Frederick, undated (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Fox, Sidney, 1971 - 1972 (Box 1, Folder 28, Box Shared Small Oversized 1)
  - Fulkerson, James, undated (Box 1, Folder 29 - 30)
  - Garrison, Wesley, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Gayles, Darlene, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Gordon, Epperson, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Gordon, Stewart, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Grande Ecurie Et La Chambre Du Roi, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Frank, Sherman, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Hautzig, Walter, 1972 - 1979 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Higdon, Jennifer, 2010 (Box Shared Small Oversized 1)
  - Hocher, Barbara, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Houlik, James and Friends, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Hrynkiv, Thomas, undated (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Hudson Valley Saxophone Quartet of West Point, undated (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Ida, Faiella, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Imig, Warner, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 43 - 44)
  - Jacquelyn, Benson, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Jane, Gunter, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Johnson, Gilbert, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Johnson, Royhamlin, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Josephine Caruso, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Kanwischer, Alfred, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Khatchurian, Aram, 1963 - 1968 (Box 1, Folder 51, Box 2, Folder 1)
  - King, Sheryl, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Kraft, Edith, undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Landwehr, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Laredo, Ruth, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Lawrence, Robert, undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Limon, Jose, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 7 - 8)
  - Lorimer, Michael, 1977 - 1978 (Box 2, Folder 9 - 10)
  - Lynn, Enid, 1971 - 1974 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Lynn, Nelga, 1974 - 1975 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Orgad Ben-zion, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - The Manhattan String Quartet, 1974 - 1975 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - The Manhattan Trio, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Marek, George, 1970 - 1972 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Mehta, Zubin, 1977 - 1979 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Michalek, Thomas, 1971 - 1973 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Mikhashoff, Yvar, 1976 - 1980 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Mischakoff, Mischa, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Morgan, Harry, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Mueller, Otto-Werner, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - New York String Quartet, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Orth, Peter, 1979 - 1980 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Paul Winter Consort, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Payne, Joseph, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Perlman, Itzhak, 1973, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Peter LaBombard, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Philadelphia String Quartet, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Phillips, Harvey, undated (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Piatigorsky, Gregor, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Quintero, Jose, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Raver, Leonard, 1971 - 1976 (Box 2, Folder 33 - 34)
  - Reich Steve & Musicians, 1974 - 1975 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Reilly, Charles Nelson, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 36 - 37)
  - Rose, Leonard, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Rostropovich, Mstilav, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Sandor, Veresa, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Schuller, Gunther, 1976 Oct (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Seeber, Leonard, 1971 - 1972 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Sherman, Russell, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Shumsky, Oscar, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 44 - 45)
  - Smith, Brooks De Wetter, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Sollenberger, Elizabeth, 1971 - 1976 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Spinelli, Henry, 1966, 1971 - 1973 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Spottiswoode, Daphne, undated (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Coombs-Stacy, Carolee, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Stan, Freeman, 1976 - 1977 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Steber, Eleanor, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Stern, Isaac, 1950, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Stradivari Quartet, 1973 - 1974 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Strasfogez, Ian, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Swarthout, Elizabeth, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Tibor, Bachmann, undated (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Tippet, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Tokyo String Quartet, 1974 - 1975 (Box 3, Folder 14 - 15)
  - Thomas, Jose, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Totenberg, Roman, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Tottle, William, 1976 Nov (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Tourel, Jennie, 1967 - 1968 (Box 3, Folder 19 - 20)
  - Turetsky, Bertram, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Tursi, Francis, 1978 - 1979 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Virginia, Brown, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Virginia, Marks, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Waesche, Woodward, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Walker, Donald, 1972, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Williams, Andy, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Winograd, Arthur, 1968, 1972-1977 (Box 3, Folder 28 - 29)
  - Yannatos, James, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Zonn, Wilma & Paul, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Zuckerman, Pinchas, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 32 - 33)
  - Miscellaneous, 1971 - 1973 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Miscellaneous, 1941, 1971, 1975, undated (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Guest Conductors - HSO Readings, 1972 - 1973 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Master Class 1971- 1972 Various Artists, 1968 - 1973 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Various - Trumpet Symposium, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Photographs
  Existence and Location of Copies
  All of the photographs in the collection have been digitized and can be accessed at: http://mdid3.hartford.edu. Public access to the digital repository is limited to the University of Hartford Campus. Computers are available to the public at the Harrison Libraries. Off-campus access is available for University of Hartford students, faculty, and staff with their university email and password.
  - American String Quartet, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Bookspan, Martin, undated (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Chase, Bill, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Crozier, Catherine, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Currier, Donald, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - De La Torre, Rey, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Duckworth, Guy, 1969 - 1970 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Garrison, Wesley, undated (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Gordon, Stewart, undated (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Heline, Carlia, undated (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Hocher, Barbara, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Imig, Warner, undated (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Kanwischer, Alfred, undated (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Khatchurian, Aram, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Kraft, Edith, undated (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Lawrence, Robert, undated (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Limon, Jose, undated (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Lorimer, Michael, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Lynn, Nelga, undated (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - The Mahattan String Quartet, 1974 - 1975 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - The Manhattan Trio, undated (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Marek, George R., undated (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Michalek, Thomas, undated (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Mikhashoff, Yvar, undated (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Orth, Peter, undated (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Payne, Joseph, undated (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Philadelphia String Quartet, undated (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Quintero, Jose, undated (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Raver, Leonard, undated (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Reilly, Charles Nelson, undated (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Schuller, Gunther, undated (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Seeber, Leonard, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Shumsky, Oscar, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Smith, Brooks Dewetter, undated (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Spinelli, Henry, undated (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Coombs-Stacy, Carolee, undated (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Steber, Eleanor, undated (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Stern, Isaac, undated (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - Swarthout, Elizabeth, undated (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - Tokyo String Quartet, undated (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - Tourel, Jennie, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - Tursi, Francis, undated (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - Waesche, Woodward, undated (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - Yannatos, James, undated (Box 4, Folder 48)
  - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 4, Folder 49)
  - Master Class- 1971-1972 Various Photos, undated (Box 4, Folder 50)